<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isolation | Adrian Crowder</title>
    <link>https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/tag/isolation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/tag/isolation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Isolation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Adrian Crowder</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Isolation</title>
      <link>https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/tag/isolation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis Topic: Low Cost Seismic Isolation</title>
      <link>https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/project/thesis-topic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://AdrianCrowder.github.io/project/thesis-topic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-topic&#34;&gt;Research Topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seismic isolation is a method of designing buildings to better withstand earthquakes. The method involves constructing a building on top of many bearings which separate the building from the ground. During an earthquake, these devices prevent violent accelerations from being passed into the building. This in turn prevents damage to the building and the contents inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous existing buildings have been upgraded with seismic isolation, but the process is often very expensive because of major alterations required at the base of the structure. The focus of my research was to make upgrades with seismic isolation more cost effective by placing the bearings on the tops of columns. This non-traditional placement can mitigate many of the costs traditionally associated with upgrades, but the interaction between the bearing and the column is not well understood. Experimental tests of a bearing connected to a column were performed, and a model was developed to predict the behaviour of the system. The research furthers the understanding of the field and will help designers create more cost effective solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experimental-work&#34;&gt;Experimental Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experimental testing of 4 subassemblies of a column and bearing were conducted at McMaster University. The test rig was designed and constructed to provide the necessary loads and displacements to the subassembies for testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A video of one of the tests with a yielding column can be viewed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/186521191&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;vimeo video&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
